hi this is Jack this is the Bashar
double cone coil which is two
interpenetrating coils their conical
shaped about 40 turns each of number 22
wire and then the that's l1 and l2 and
l3 it's just about another 40 turns
wrapped around and then open-ended so
what I have here is the super laser
Sabre circuit with lid motors and laser
sabers and hooked up with this thing so
it will have a load of a light bulb and
then the l3 behavior is produces a lot
of high voltage so here again is the
single active element the two and three
oh five five and the load is off of one
side of the one of the coils to ground
in the third coil here l3 is the one
that's wrapped around the middle of both
of the conical coils but here's a here's
the circuit oval it's steady so you can
check that out and now moving back to
the circuit we have a light we're using
about six watts total on this 120 volt
small light it's using a couple of watts
but the curious thing is that the I
can't measure this high voltage if you
touch one side of the neon this is the L
3 output which has probably a thousand
at 1200 or 1300 volts it shocks you and
it it it really does shock you and if
you load it too much it will kill the
oscillations as you can see there that
it load it will um line up and then but
the curious thing is see how it the
filament on the bulb goes out to goes
dimmer when you load it with various
things you can use AV plugs as well for
the load and in those work as well and I
tried to measure it on the
but and it freaks out my meters so I
don't know it's at least a thousand
volts probably higher and one curious
thing is that if you look at the load
the overall load is six point one but
then when you load it the encoding drops
to say five point four or five point
three that's the overall load for the
system through the brick so apparently
you can load the system and it will use
less power so I don't know if you can
scale that very well or what but thing
that's curious about this is just one
active element there's the two and three
oh five five and that's it and the coils
and the load and that's all there is to
it
then I give you a shot of the coil again
and thanks for watching